For loops iterate over every element in a sequence,
for 循环会遍历一个序列中的所有元素
and while loops iterate until they're stopping condition is met.
而 while 循环会一直迭代 直到满足停止条件
This is sufficient for most purposes but we
对于大多数情况来说 这两种循环都足够了
sometimes need more precise control over when a loop should end.
但有时候需要更精确地控制何时应该停止循环
In these cases, we use the break keyword.
在这些情况下 我们将使用关键字 break
A loop will terminate immediately if it encounters a break statement.
循环遇到 break 语句后将立即停止
We can use this to end the loop if we detect that some condition has been met.
如果我们检测到满足某个条件 可以使用该关键字结束循环
The break keyword can be used in both for and while loops.
关键字 break 可以同时用在 for 和 while 循环中
For example, suppose you want to load a cargo ship with a list of items called manifest.
例如 假设你想向货船上装载货物清单中的货物
This list contains tuples of items and their weights.
该列表包含货物和重量元组
Ideally, you would like to load all the items on
理想情况下 你希望将所有货物都装载到货船上
the ship but the ship has a maximum weight capacity.
但是货船有重量上限
Therefore, when the ship's capacity is reached,
因此 当达到货船的重量上限时
you want to stop loading.
你想要停止装载货物
To accomplish this, let's use a for loop loading
为了满足这一要求 我们使用 for 循环
each item and keeping track of the weight of all the items we have loaded so far.
装载货物并记录到目前为止装载的所有货物的重量
Here, we check if the ship's total cargo weight reaches
在每次添加一个货物时
its maximum capacity of 100 with each addition of cargo.
我们都将检查货船的总货物重量是否达到最大容量 100
If it does, we use a break statement to stop loading.
如果达到了 则使用 break 语句停止装载货物
If not, we load the next item and add on its weight.
如果没达到 则装载下个货物并加上它的重量
Here's what we end up loading.
最终装载了这些货物
That's not good.
情况不妙
The boat is severely over its weight limit of 100.
货船的货物重量远远超出了上限 100
The break statement did prevent us from putting every item on
break 语句的确阻止我们将所有货物放入货船中
the boat but we still exceeded the limit by 111.
但是我们依然比上限多出了 111
It's difficult to see what's gone wrong.
很难看出哪里出错了
One strategy we can use is to add print statements in the code.
一种策略是在代码中添加 print 语句
This is a really handy technique as it can give us some insight
这是一个非常实用的技巧
into what happens in the code as it's running step-by-step.
因为它可以帮助我们了解代码逐步运行时发生了什么情况
Having print statements frequently that give context can
添加多个提供背景信息的 print 语句
really assist us in understanding what went wrong here.
可以有效帮助我们了解哪里出错了
Here's the loop with debugging statements added.
这是添加调试语句后的循环
Debugging is the process of identifying and removing errors in your code.
调试是指找出代码中的错误并消除错误的流程
Here, we can see that we didn't break until the weight exceeded 100,
在此示例中 可以看出直到重量超出 100 才跳出循环
when really, we should break before that item is added.
实际上 我们应该在添加该货物之前就跳出循环
Additionally, we can see that the cheeses still could
此外 可以看出如果不添加机器的话
have fit if the machine wasn't added.
依然可以装载芝士
This brings us to another statement.
这就要提到另一个语句
Sometimes, rather than breaking out of the loop completely,
有时候 我们需要跳过一次循环迭代
there will be times we want to skip simply one iteration of the loop.
而不是完全退出循环
In this case, we would use the continue keyword.
在这种情况下 我们可以使用关键字 continue
In this example, we iterate through a list of
在此示例中 我们遍历一个食品列表
foods and increment account if the food is a fruit.
如果食品是水果 则使计数器递增
Here, we terminate an iteration if the food is not found in fruit.
如果 fruit 中没有该食品 则停止迭代
Otherwise, we add one to fruit count.
否则 使 fruit_count 加一
So when food is hummus or toast in this loop,
当这次循环的食品是鹰嘴豆泥或吐司时
the rest of the loop is completely skipped.
循环的剩余部分完全被跳过